

Guilherme Morone Araujo

Nationality: Brazilian Date of birth: 10 Feb 2001 Gender: Male

Email address: guimorone@gmail.com

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/guimorone

Website: https://guimorone.github.io

ABOUT ME

Originally from Rio but now based in Recife, I've had the privilege of growing up in two vibrant cities. My passions are as diverse as my background, ranging from an avid love for games and books to an insatiable curiosity for travel and technology. Furthermore, I am always eager to explore new opportunities and challenges that can help me grow both as a professional and as a person, fuelled by my passion for learning and applying new technologies to solve real-world problems.

I have been working on Software Development since 2020, and I am used to developing Big Data applications that demand high efficiency, scalability, and low cost. All my projects demanded skills in web development, data engineering, CI/CD, Docker, GitHub Actions, and cloud computing, in order to deliver quality solutions to clients.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor in Computer Engineering

Federal University of Pernambuco (UFPE) [1 Feb 2019 - 31 Aug 2024]

City: Recife | Country: Brazil | Website: https://portal.cin.ufpe.br | Field(s) of study: Information and Communication Technologies: • Software and applications development and analysis • Computer use • Database and network design and administration • Information and communication technologies not elsewhere classified • Information and Communication Technologies (ICTs) not further defined; Engineering, manufacturing and construction: • Electronics and automation | Final grade: 9.02/10.0 | Level in EQF: EQF level 6

Link: https://repositorio.ufpe.br/handle/123456789/58235

Student Teaching Assistant

Federal University of Pernambuco (UFPE) [1 Jun 2022 – 31 Mar 2024]

Website: https://portal.cin.ufpe.br | Field(s) of study: Information and Communication Technologies: ● Software and applications development and analysis

- Dedicated Student Teaching Assistant in the field of Software and Systems Engineering.
- Provided invaluable support to students in software development and requirements engineering, with a primary goal of crafting top-tier applications of exceptional quality.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Neurotech [10 Apr 2024 – Current]

City: Recife | Country: Brazil | Website: https://www.neurotech.com.br | Email address: guilherme.morone@neurotech.com.

br | Name of unit or department: Hydra - Neurolake

Full-time job:

- In general, using skills in software, data engineering and backend development with Python, FastAPI, Terraform, Git, Airflow, Bash and cloud computing on AWS.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to achieve project goals.
- Ensure high-quality, scalable application development.
- Using AWS solutions such as Lambda, DynamoDB, EC2, Athena, S3, Step Functions and more.
- Extract data from different sources and make it available for many users in a data lake.

Full Stack Developer

GPC Gestão [3 Sep 2024 – 9 Oct 2024]

City: Recife | Country: Brazil | Website: https://gpcgestao.com.br

Freelancer:

• Built an admin website using React with TypeScript and Tailwind CSS.

Software Engineer

Jalan [10 Apr 2024 – 31 May 2024]

City: Recife | Country: Brazil | Website: https://jalan.com.br

Full-time job:

· Worked as a Full Stack developer using Vue.js and Quasar along with Python and Lambda Functions (AWS).

Mobile Engineer

aca.so [1 Mar 2024 - 31 Mar 2024]

City: Recife | Country: Brazil | Website: https://aca.so

Freelancer:

• Worked as a Mobile Engineer in a project (aca.so mobile app) using React Native.

Software Engineer

Oncase [1 Feb 2022 – 28 Dec 2023]

City: Recife | Country: Brazil | Website: https://www.oncase.com.br

Full-time job:

- Developed Big Data applications with a focus on high efficiency, scalability, and low cost.
- Developed frontend applications using React (JavaScript, TypeScript and HTML/CSS) and Redux.
- Implemented backend functionality using Python frameworks Flask and Django.
- Implemented effective CI/CD pipelines for seamless integration and deployment through Docker and GitHub Actions.
- In general, utilized skills in web development (Django, React and HTML/CSS), data engineering, CI/CD, Docker, GitHub Actions, and cloud computing.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to achieve project goals.
- Enhanced customer relationships through the delivery of top-notch solutions.
- Ensured high-quality and scalable application development.
- Hosted applications on Google Cloud Platform using Cloud Run and Artifact Registry.
- Utilized Amazon Web Services for hosting, leveraging services like Amplify, Route53, and Lambda.

Mobile Engineer

InSpace [1 Aug 2022 – 31 Oct 2022]

City: Recife | Country: Brazil | Website: https://inspace.tech

Freelancer:

• I have worked with the identification of objects (censored specificity) from a mobile camera for legal purposes.

Game Developer

Educandus [1 May 2020 – 30 Dec 2020]

City: Recife | Country: Brazil | Website: https://educandus.com.br

Internship:

• I have worked as a game developer using Construct 3 software and JavaScript, building educational games for students from preschool to high school levels.

Game Developer

Educandus [1 Jun 2021 – 31 Oct 2021]

City: Recife | Country: Brazil | Website: https://educandus.com.br

Internship:

• I have worked as a game developer using Construct 3 software and JavaScript, building educational games for students from preschool to high school levels.

COURSES AND CERTIFICATIONS

[7 Nov 2024 - 12 Nov 2024]

GraphQL by Example

Skills learned/improved:

- GraphQL
- · React.js
- Node.js
- JavaScript
- TypeScript

Link: https://ude.my/UC-2f72d8c0-5e8c-4c08-a657-cb379948c6f1

[1 Nov 2024 - 7 Nov 2024]

The Complete Cyber Security Course - Volume 1: Hackers Exposed!

Skills learned/improved:

- Cybersecurity
- Linux

Link: https://ude.my/UC-1acdc51c-9652-40d8-80af-24d65aa27727

[15 Mar 2024 - 3 Apr 2024]

The Complete Flutter Development Bootcamp with Dart

Skills learned/improved:

- Flutter
- Firebase
- Cloud Firestore
- Google Cloud Platform (GCP)

Link: https://ude.my/UC-3fd9599a-bff2-4960-8d34-dbb3b41ced55

[1 Mar 2023 – 14 Mar 2023]

Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Data, ML, and Al in Google Cloud - Locales

Credential ID: 3311200

Skills learned/improved:

- Google Cloud Platform (GCP)
- Cloud Computing

Link: https://www.cloudskillsboost.google/public_profiles/d8f54101-4f80-4aee-8e46-2320e3e20646/badges/3311200

[1 Mar 2023 – 13 Mar 2023]

Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Infrastructure in Google Cloud - Locales

Credential ID: 3303084

Skills learned/improved:

- Google Cloud Platform (GCP)
- Cloud Computing
- Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD)

Link: https://www.cloudskillsboost.google/public_profiles/d8f54101-4f80-4aee-8e46-2320e3e20646/badges/3303084

[1 Mar 2023 – 13 Mar 2023]

Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Networking & Security - Locales

Credential ID: 3305980

Skills learned/improved:

Google Cloud Platform (GCP)

- Cloud Computing
- Cybersecurity

Link: https://www.cloudskillsboost.google/public_profiles/d8f54101-4f80-4aee-8e46-2320e3e20646/badges/3305980

[1 Mar 2023 - 12 Mar 2023]

Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Cloud Computing Fundamentals - Locales

Credential ID: 3302433

Skills learned/improved:

- Google Cloud Platform (GCP)
- Cloud Computing

Link: https://www.cloudskillsboost.google/public_profiles/d8f54101-4f80-4aee-8e46-2320e3e20646/badges/3302433

[1 Apr 2020 - 21 Apr 2020]

The Complete 2020 Web Development Bootcamp

Skills learned/improved:

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Node.js
- React.js + React Hooks
- Git
- REST APIs
- JQuery
- HTML
- CSS
- SQL
- MongoDB

Link: https://ude.my/UC-5d594204-a414-4cb1-a388-72e3daf7c1c6

PROJECTS

[1 Jul 2023 – 28 Dec 2023]

Cheque Fácil

- Website made with 3 more colleagues to an external customer.
- The main purpose is to identify bank check fields easily, so you do not have to type manually.
- The bank check OCR is based on our customer's API, we did not implement it, just the website.
- It also offers API Integration, history download and other features.

Skills/Technologies: Django · TypeScript · Software Development · React.js · Redux.js · React Hooks · Tailwind CSS · Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD) · Docker · Linux · Shell.

[27 Feb 2023 – 26 Apr 2023]

Type War

A 2D game made with other college colleagues. Inspired in the famous ZType game, but in Portuguese. Skills/Technologies: Game Development \cdot React.js \cdot React Hooks \cdot Tailwind CSS \cdot Programming \cdot TypeScript.

Links: https://type-war-game-cin.vercel.app | https://github.com/guimorone/projeto-jogos | https://zty.pe

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Portuguese

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING C1 READING C2 WRITING C2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

German

LISTENING A2 READING A2 WRITING A2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION A2 **SPOKEN INTERACTION** A2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS TEST RESULTS

	Information and data literacy	ADVANCED	Level 6 / 6
®# #©	Communication and collaboration	ADVANCED	Level 6 / 6
©	Digital content creation	ADVANCED	Level 6 / 6
	Safety	ADVANCED	Level 6 / 6
4	Problem solving	ADVANCED	Level 6 / 6

Results from a <u>self-assessment</u> based on <u>The Digital Competence Framework 2.1</u>